One of the dynamics of this war has been
the president going out there saying,
"We are talking to somebody. I can't
tell you who it is cuz I'm worried he'll
get killed." And then of course left
unsaid is killed by who? Obviously, it's
the Israelis. So, what was your
experience with them? It was universally
negative.
Uh on
in my very first briefing, I had only
been on the job as an Iraq analyst for 6
weeks.
My boss said to me, "I want you to
participate in a group briefing. You're
going to brief the Israelis. They have a
Shin Bet representative and a Mossad
representative." And he said, "We don't
We don't speak to the Israelis in the
building. They're not permitted in the
building because every time they would
come to CIA headquarters, they would
bring gifts and the gifts were always
laden with listening devices and
batteries and you know, we we would
x-ray everything and and we would tell
them stop trying to bug our conference
rooms." And they would say, "Oh
Okay. Okay. You caught us. Okay."
So, finally we said, "They just can't
come in anymore." So, we we have a safe
house where we meet with the Israelis.
So, it was like eight of us.
The senior Iraq analyst, the military
analyst, the political analyst, the econ
analyst, the oil analyst, everybody's
doing their thing. And because I was the
most junior, I went last.
And um
I said because I was an overt employee,
"My name is John Kiriakou and I'm going
to brief you today on Saddam Hussein's
state of mind." And the Mossad
representative looked over his glasses
at me and he said, uh "Spell your name?"
So, I spelled it and he says to me in
front of everybody, he says, "You are
Jewish?"
And I said, "I am not recruitable. Don't
even think about trying to recruit me.
Shame on you."
So, I went back to the office. My boss
said, "How did it go?" I said, "I'm so
angry right now I could explode." I
said, "He practically pitched me right
there in the meeting and asked if I was
Jewish." And he laughed and he said,
"They've done that to every single one
of us."
On my Trying to get you to turn against
your country for them.
>> them. On my very first day at the CIA,
where you know, you you put your hand up
in the air and you swear to uphold and
protect the Constitution against all
enemies foreign and domestic.
Uh we had a briefing by the CIA's
director of security.
And he told us that there are two
intelligence representatives at the
Israeli embassy. One from Mossad, one
from Shin Bet. He said, "But the FBI has
been able to identify 187
other undeclared Israeli intelligence
officers spread out all across America
working to steal secrets from American
defense contractors."
But politically
the relationship is so close that you
don't want to rock the boat
and uh you know, start arresting people
spying for Israel. Look at Jonathan
Pollard. He does every day of a 30-year
sentence and then is welcomed like some
kind of a conquering hero at the
American embassy in Jerusalem Jerusalem.
It made me sick to my stomach.
Well, when you said that comment about
how everybody in Congress is afraid of
the CIA, the same is true when it comes
to Israel. I don't know if afraid is the
word, but but controlled by I mean, one
of the dynamics of this the wake of the
Iran war, John, has been
the
not just like the loudest, but kind of
the only front-facing critics have been
from the more isolationist right. Where
are the Democrats? Oh, where are they?
>> That's That's the
>> That's the question right there. Where
in the world are the Democrats? They are
utterly silent. In fact, I'll tell you,
I was especially furious with Cory
Booker, the Democratic senator from New
Jersey. Not the last time
Netanyahu came to Washington, but the
time before Cory Booker literally ran
through the halls of Congress
to get to a photo op so he could stand
behind Benjamin Netanyahu with his big
stupid grin on his face. Like even now
after Gaza, after the start of Iran,
now you're running like O.J. Simpson
through an airport in in the old I'm
dating myself, but in the old whatever
it was commercial. Yeah, Hertz
commercial.
You want to be in a picture with
Benjamin Netanyahu.
Uh some of them are afraid of being
primaried. And and God knows that that
AIPAC, if you are not 100% pro-Israel in
your voting record, they will primary
you and they will spend millions of
dollars to defeat you. That scares
most
members of Congress. And so they're just
not willing to challenge anybody. I'll
tell you another thing. I used to be the
chief investigator on the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee. I did that from '09
to '11.
And um
a couple of days after I started the
job, uh these two guys came in, clearly
obviously from AIPAC, and they said,
"Hey, welcome to Capitol Hill." I said,
"Thanks, I've worked on Capitol Hill
before."
Um we want to invite you for an all
expenses paid trip to the Holy Land.
They didn't say Israel. Totally.
>> I said, "Thanks, guys. I can pay for my
own vacations. I'm not interested. It's
all expenses paid and we're going to
take you to all the Christian holy
sites." I go, "Guys,
I'm not taking AIPAC's money.
I'm not interested."
But I don't think a single day went by
where I didn't see those two.
They were they practically had offices
up there. And then individual House
members say that there are AIPAC reps
that will go to their office every day
and just sit on the couch.
And if constituents come in
to meet with staff or to meet with the
member of Congress. These guys will get
up like it's their office and say,
"Remember Israel. Israel Israel Israel.
Remember."
Like, what is that?
That's That's not the American way.
>> I I think that the manipulation is so
ubiquitous, you almost just don't even
know it's happening because everyone's
singing from the same hymnal. And so
it's like, "Yeah, this is what we all
think." I remember at Fox News, it was
like a knee-jerk thing. You had to say
like, "In Israel, we have a very special
relationship. You know, they're our most
important ally in the Middle East." And
every once in a while I would remember
to ask, "Why?"
>> Why? Why again? Like You know. to have
somebody explain that to me.
>> Yes. And it always kind of petered out
after that. Like, "Why again?" It was
always about demonizing the Arab states.
You know, we're supposed to hate them
because they're Muslim. We're supposed
to love Israel because they're
supposedly with us in the
Judeo-Christian uh you know,
yeah, narrative. I I It's There's been
such a manipulation paid for a paid for
manipulation that I think many of us
just starting to see, John.
>> Benjamin Netanyahu said something that
was very um
very much overlooked and I think very
disturbing. Last week he was giving He
He had given a speech and an Israeli
reporter asked him a question about the
American-Israeli war against Iran.
And he corrected her and he said, "It's
the American war against Iran. We are
America's ally." And I thought, "Oh,
buddy, that's not what you were saying 2
weeks ago."
Now Now we stand alone doing your dirty
work.
But that's what it's come down to.
That's clearly where it is and he's
already saying there are many reports
out from Israeli TV saying, "If we do go
boots on the ground, it won't be with
them."
>> They're They're boots on the ground in
Lebanon. They've got another issue
they've taken on where a million
Lebanese have been displaced because
really Israel wants to be the hegemon of
the region and saw an opportunity here.
And so we'll be on our own. It'll be
American blood and treasure. That spills
on
cargo island. Not exactly our
>> Right? Our super tight allies.
>> Yes.
Thanks for watching this clip. If you're
new here, subscribe. We got a whole lot
more goodness where that came from.
Would love to hear your feedback. You
can email me, too. megan, m e g y n at
megankelly.com, or just leave a comment
below. But, join the community by
becoming a subscriber. We really, really
value your input and your support. We
may not always agree, but we are always
going to talk about it and respect. No
BS, no agenda, no fear. Think about
this. In 2006, $20,000 equaled roughly
33 oz of gold at spot price. At today's
prices, those 33 oz would be worth about
$165,000.
That's why many smart Americans
diversify a portion of their savings
into precious metals. And that's why you
should consider buying gold from Birch
Gold Group. For thousands of years, gold
has been a store of wealth. And today,
it's a crucial part of any balanced
strategy. Even better, Birch Gold can
help you convert an existing IRA or 401k
into a tax-sheltered retirement account
in gold. Just text MK to the number
989898 to receive your free info kit on
gold. There's no obligation, just useful
information. With an A+ rating with the
Better Business Bureau and tens of
thousands of happy customers, let Birch
Gold help you diversify with gold. Now,
that's peace of mind. Again, text MK to
today.